

# **ABOUT ME:**

Accomplished corporate and independent entrepreneur and business developer with a strong interest in digital solutions and technology. 10+ years experience within business development, technology and innovation.

I love to bring commercial business ideas into reality as building and creating digital solutions is a strong passion of mine.

Extensive knowledge and experience from technology, business development, innovation, product development, management, digital marketing, growth, e-commerce, team management and user experience.

#### HIGHLIGHTS:

- Co-Founder of <u>Fraxx.co</u>, a Norwegian online course platform
- Maker of <u>Fabrik.no</u> one of the fastest growing ecommerce sites in Norway
- Finalist, Entrepreneur of the Year. Nordic Women in Tech Awards 2022.
- Former External Lecturer, Copenhagen Business
   School, Department of IT Management
- Former Chair Woman, Licensee, and Co. Organizer at TEDxCopenhagen

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

FRAXX INTERACTIVE, OSLO
Co-Founder, April 2019 - Now

Fraxx.co is a Norwegian digital course platform on a mission to raise the bar for digital learning in the b2c-market. Today we have sold more than 12.000 courses. In 2022 Fraxx was nominated "Growth startup of the Year" by Tripletex and in 2020 we were awarded a business grant by Facebook. Building Fraxx has put my entire toolbox to use and I have gained significnt experience from starting a business from scratch. From building the very first MVP with the tech-team to scaling the platform into a commercial product loved by our customers and community.

Alongside building Fraxx I have also been highly involved in building the digital and commercial part of Fæbrik - a sewing community led by Jenny Skavlan. I built the ecommerce site <u>faebrik.no</u> and worked closely with the 4 founders in the development of the digital platform.

BONNIER MEDIA, OSLO

Head of Business Development, 2018 - 2019

Responsible for developing new digital products and services for Bonnier Norway and Denmark. I was a part of the mangement team in Norway.

# HELLE-VIBEKE SCHÜTTE

+47 91928120 | hellexvibeke@gmail.com | Oslo, Norway

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# FRONTIER CONSULTING, COPENHAGEN

 $/\!/$  Innovation, digitalization & business development 2017 - 2018

Helping companies to unfold their potential within innovation, concept development, and digitalization. I worked with the following companies; **Bonnier** (media), **Atea** & **RFRSH** (Astralis esport).

# TWENTYTHREE APS, COPENHAGEN

**Chief of Staff** // Start-up, People & Innovation 2017 - 2017

TwentyThree is a SaaS start-up making tools for visual sharing. TwentyThree has offices in Copenhagen and San Francisco. I was in charge of the overall OKR implementation and follow ups as well as assisting the CEO in management decisions for future growth.

# COPENHAGEN BUSINESS SCHOOL

**External Lecturer**, Department of IT-Management 2016 - 2017.

External Lecturer at Copenhagen Business School, Institute of IT Management. Teaching and responsible for the course Organizations, Innovation, and Information Systems, approx 50 students.

# ABTION SOFTWARE, COPENHAGEN

**COO** // Technology & Innovation. 2015 - 2016

My role as COO was to take care of the daily operations in collaboration with our CEO. Furthermore, I was responsible for both hiring and for maintaining our client portfolio. It was my responsibility to identify and solve client's problems and challenges using software, digitalization, and best technology practice together with the team.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

HD MADE LLC. NEW YORK

**Project Manager** // Strategy & Innovation 2015 - 2015.

I was hired at HD MADE to jumpstart the startup phase of Canal Street Market in New York. Canal Street Market aims to create a new innovative physical/digital retail space and give established and upcoming brands, concepts and media platforms a test-lab in order to rethink how we understand retail, food experiences, partnerships and the interaction with today's digital consumer.

# OPENBOX LLC. NEW YORK

**Innovation Fellow** // Innovation & Design Thinking 2015 - 2015.

Openbox is a design thinking and innovation consultancy that empowers organizations and communities to shift the way they think, build, and grow together.

At Openbox, my main role was to combine my traditional business competencies with design thinking in order to build a bridge and solve business-related problems.

# WISHBONE APS, COPENHAGEN

Project Manager // IT & Sales. 2012 - 2014

At WishBone I was responsible for an incubator concept focused on new innovation within sales and IT-processes on behalf of the leading Danish provider of communication solutions, TDC. Because of this new software and concept, TDC had a remarkable growth rate of 229% within this business area after Y1. Today, the concept has turned into an independent company and has 20+ employees.

# HELLE-VIBEKE SCHÜTTE

+47 91928120 | hellexvibeke@gmail.com | Oslo, Norway

# OTHER:

# MINISTRY OF HIGHER EDUCATION AND SCIENCE **Appointed Censor, Digital Business Development**2018 - 2021

# HACK4GIRIS.ORG

Project Lead, 2017

Hack4Girls is a hackathon to support the health and safety of refugee girls and women in Africa. In October 2017 we gathered 70 software developers, designers, data scientists and business minds in Copenhagen for a 36-hour hackathon to work on tomorrow's solutions for refugee girls and women.

# SANDBOX NETWORK

Ambassador. 2015 -2020

The Sandbox Network is a global community that works across sectors, borders, and cultures and aims to help its members strive for their best potential.

Sandbox identifies and brings together the world's most inspiring young leaders and accelerates them from the point of local impact to global influence.

#### **EDUCATION:**

# SINGULARITY UNIVERSITY

Executive Program, 2017, Palo Alto, CA. Accepted among business leaders from all over the world.

#### AARHUS SCHOOL OF BUSINESS

Master of Science in Business Administration and Commercial Law, 2009 - 2011.

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration and Commercial Law, 2006 - 2009.

# LinkedIn profile here

# OTHER:

# **TED**×**COPENHAGEN**

Licensee & Co. Organizer. 2013 - 2014

TEDxCopenhagen is a satellite organization with a license from TED, a license that was given to me personally from TED.

Areas of responsibilities: Community building, operations, and leadership. Co-organising events, counseling and motivating event teams and more than 80 volunteers. Representing Denmark and Danish ideas worth spreading at international TED conferences. Building an international network within the TED community in order to open doors for Danish initiatives, ideas and game changers.

# #CPHFTW, COPENHAGEN

#CPHFTW is a grass-roots organization that aims to strengthen the tech startup ecosystem of Copenhagen.

I helped the team behind #CPHFTW to organize their first Townhall event with almost 800 attendees. The purpose of the event was to gather and strengthen the Copenhagen startup community.

- Invited by the Malaysian Government to contribute to cluster sessions on innovation at Global Entrepreneurship Conference 2016 in Kuala Lumpur.
- Former member of the Scandinavian Nova Pro Talent Network.
- On the winning team for the best startup with biggest social impact at Startup Weekend at the Danish Parliament, 2013.

# HELLE-VIBEKE SCHÜTTE

+47 91928120 | hellexvibeke@gmail.com | Oslo, Norway

# **SKILLS:**

# MARKET- AND USER RESEARCH:

Qualitative and quantitative research, identify consumer behaviour and needs

# **DESIGN THINKING:**

Studied IDEO's human-centered design tools and methods in NYC

#### DIGITAL CONCEPT DEVELOPMENT:

Business Model Canvas by Osterwalder and The Design Sprint by Google Ventures

# **BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT:**

Strategy, team and talent development, business proposals, project management, risk assessment, KPI's/OKR's

# TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGEMENT:

Team management, the principles of agile methodology, technical architecture and project management

# **DIGITAL MARKETING:**

Strategy and implementation, META and Snapchat advertising, CRM and community building

# **E-COMMERCE**:

Strategy, website building, payment solutions, GDPR, customer service and satisfaction

# **CONSULTING:**

Proposals, client lead, meetings and pitches, projectand team lead

# **TEACHING:**

Facilitating work shops and teaching lectures

# TEAM MANAGEMENT:

Managed dev. team, marketing team, content team, been in charge of hiring processes and decision making, employee development, 1:1's, leadership and motivation.

# **TOOLBOX:**

# **ADMIN & PROJECT MANAGEMENT:**

G-Suite, Asana, Jira, Airtable & Trello

# **DESIGN & COLLABORATION:**

Canva, Miro & Firma

#### TECH:

Heroku, Stripe, Quickpay, Vipps, Github, AWS & Shopify

#### HR:

Workable

#### MARKETING

Meta Business Suite, Klaviyo & Google Analytics

#### LANGUAGE:

- English
- Danish
- Norwegian